OK.
好的。
So in this lesson we've been talking about lots of different time words and phrases.
所以在本课中，我们一直在讨论许多不同的时间词和短语。
And now we're down to the very last one whenever and every time.
现在我们每次都到最后一个。
Basically this means there's an event here an event here an event here an event here.
基本上这意味着这里有一个事件，这里有一个事件，这里有一个事件，这里有一个事件。
And each one of these events has a thing that happens in all cases.
这些事件中的每一个都有在所有情况下都会发生的事情。
It's not like there's an event event event event.
它不像有一个事件事件事件事件。
And this one this one and this one have something happen but not this one.
而这个这个这个和这个有一些事情发生，但不是这个。
OK.
好的。
No then we can't use whenever or every time if we want to use whenever or every time it has to be all
不，如果我们想随时随地使用它，我们就不能随时随地使用
of them.
其中。
For example whenever I teach a class I make a plan.
例如，每当我教课时，我都会制定计划。
Whenever I teach a class I make a plan.
每当我教课时，我都会制定计划。
That means there are no times when I don't make a plan.
这意味着我没有不制定计划的时候。
I always have a plan.
我总是有一个计划。
I always have an outline.
我总是有一个大纲。
I know what I'm going to talk about.
我知道我要谈什么。
I don't just come out and go blah blah blah and start talking.
我不只是出来然后去胡说八道然后开始说话。
OK let's look at some examples of this.
好的，让我们看一些例子。
It's a pretty easy concept whenever and every time are basically the same.
这是一个非常简单的概念，无论何时何地都基本相同。
Whenever I feel is more common.
每当我觉得是比较常见的。
But every time is ok too.
但每次都还可以。
Whenever whenever I visit New York City I go to Danny's pizza in Queens and Danny's pizza in Queens.
每当我访问纽约市时，我都会去皇后区的丹尼披萨店和皇后区的丹尼披萨店。
Very good.
很好。
Very tasty.
非常好吃。
You're welcome.
别客气。
Danny's pizza for the free advertised man.
丹尼为免费广告人做的披萨。
Seriously it's a place in Queens.
说真的，这是皇后区的一个地方。
It has amazing pizza the best pizza in the world in my opinion.
它有很棒的披萨，在我看来是世界上最好的披萨。
OK so that means there are no times that I go to New York and don't visit Danny's pizza.
好的，这意味着我没有时间去纽约不去丹尼的披萨店。
OK.
好的。
I could also say every time I visit New York City I go to Danny's pizza in Queens.
我也可以说，每次我访问纽约市时，我都会去皇后区的丹尼披萨店。
Another example every time we have class I see you improving.
另一个例子，每次我们上课时，我都看到你在进步。
We could say whenever we have class I see you improving every time.
我们可以说，每当我们上课时，我都会看到你每次都在进步。
OK.
好的。
So in these cases we can see that every time and whenever are the same but are they ever different.
所以在这些情况下，我们可以看到每次和任何时候都是相同的，但它们是否不同。
The answer is yes we can use whenever also to mean any time or I don't care.
答案是肯定的，我们可以用任何时候也表示任何时候，或者我不在乎。
Just choose a time and that's OK with me.
只要选择一个时间，我就可以了。
For example one friend says to another what time.
例如，一位朋友对另一位朋友说什么时间。
What time should we should we leave.
我们应该什么时候离开。
One friend is asking to another friend the other Francis.
一位朋友正在向另一位朋友询问另一位弗朗西斯。
Whenever that means I don't care when any time is up to you.
每当这意味着我不在乎什么时候取决于你。
We can't use every time here.
我们不能每次都在这里使用。
We can't say every time it doesn't work.
我们不能每次都说它不起作用。
It doesn't work.
它不起作用。
So this is a place where whenever has a meaning or a use that doesn't include every time it doesn't
所以这是一个地方，无论何时都有意义或用途，不包括每次不包括
include every time there's also a situation when we would use every time but not whenever and it's usually
包括每次也有一种情况，我们每次都会使用，但不是每次都使用，通常是
at the end of a sentence.
在句末。
For example I'm not looking forward to going to New York.
例如，我不期待去纽约。
So why can you imagine I get lost every time.
所以你为什么能想象我每次都迷路。
So here is where we can use every time but not whenever I'm not looking forward to going to New York.
所以这里是我们每次都可以使用的地方，但不是在我不期待去纽约的时候。
I get lost every time.
我每次都迷路。
That means every time I go.
这意味着我每次去。
But we can end the sentence with every time and we couldn't just replace that with whenever I get lost
但是我们可以用每次来结束这句话，我们不能只是用每当我迷路时替换它
whenever it doesn't doesn't make sense.
每当它没有意义。
We can say every time but not whenever there.
我们可以说每次，但不是每次都在那里。
We could say I get lost when ever I go there.
我们可以说我去那里时迷路了。
But then it's kind of a weird sentence.
但这是一个奇怪的句子。
And we're saying too much.
而且我们说的太多了。
I get lost every time that we could add every time I do as well every time I do.
每次我们都迷路了每次我做的时候都可以添加。
Every time I go there.
每次我去那里。
But the nice thing about every time at the end of the sentence is that we can end that way.
但是每次在句尾的好处是我们可以这样结束。
I'm not looking forward to going to New York.
我不期待去纽约。
I get lost every time.
我每次都迷路。
It can also be used to answer a question that somebody asks and we can't use whenever.
它也可以用来回答有人问的问题，我们不能随时使用。
Do you throw up when you drink rum answer every time not whenever we can't say whenever whenever can
当你喝朗姆酒时你会呕吐吗？回答每次不是每次我们不能说无论何时何时可以
go into a whole sentence.
进入一个完整的句子。
Whenever I drink rum I throw up.
每当我喝朗姆酒时，我都会呕吐。
That works.
这样可行。
But if we want to just answer the question with this every time we can.
但是，如果我们想每次都用这个来回答这个问题。
That's the answer every time yes every time.
每次都是这样，每次都是。
Which means every time I drink rum I throw up.
这意味着每次我喝朗姆酒我都会呕吐。
OK.
好的。
So hopefully that's clear the difference between whenever and every time.
所以希望这清楚地表明了每次和每次之间的区别。
All right.
所以我们经历了很多与时间有关的单词和短语。
I hope that you found it very useful.
我希望你发现它非常有用。
Again these are all very common to really remember all the words and phrases that we've learned in this
同样，这些都是非常常见的，可以真正记住我们在本文中学到的所有单词和短语
lesson.
课。
You've got to practice so write down all of the examples that we went through in this lesson.
你必须练习所以写下我们在这节课中经历的所有例子。
I know there are many because we went through lots of different time words and phrases.
我知道有很多，因为我们经历了很多不同的时间单词和短语。
Write them down and then make two sentences of your own.
把它们写下来，然后自己造两句话。
This will help to get them deeply grain in your mind so that when you need to speak and use them because
这将有助于在您的脑海中深入了解它们，以便在您需要说话和使用它们时，因为
they're very common they need to come out on a regular basis when you need to use them they will pop
它们很常见，当您需要使用它们时，它们需要定期出现，它们会弹出
out of your mouth like nothing will be very easy.
从你的嘴里想出什么事都不会很容易。
OK.
好的。
Good luck.
祝你好运。